♪
Asuna: TAKE ME TO KIRITO.
Higa: WELL, THERE YOU GO.
I TOLD YOU YOUR BOY
WAS THE BIGGEST THREAT
TO THIS PROJECT’S SECURITY.
Kikuoka: I KNOW.
YOU DON’T HAVE TO RUB IT IN.
Asuna: IS KIRITO
EVEN SAFE HERE?!
WERE YOU LYING WHEN YOU SAID
YOU COULD SAVE HIM?
IS HE ALIVE?! ANSWER ME!
( Kikuoka sighs )
KANEMOTO INJECTED
A POTENT TOXIN INTO HIM.
IT DAMAGED
KIRITO’S BRAIN SO MUCH,
CONVENTIONAL TREATMENT
CAN’T HEAL HIM.
( Asuna shudders )
Kikuoka: BUT
UNCONVENTIONAL TREATMENT CAN,
AND THE ONLY PLACE
WITH THAT TECHNOLOGY IS RATH.
( Asuna gasps )
Kikuoka: I’M SURE
HE TOLD YOU ABOUT IT,
THE S.T.L.,
SHORT FOR "SOUL TRANSLATOR."
IF WE USE THE S.T.L.
TO STIMULATE HIS FLUCTLIGHT,
WE CAN REGENERATE
A BRAND-NEW,
PERFECTLY HEALTHY
NEURAL NETWORK,
BUT THAT TAKES TIME.
RIGHT NOW,
HE’S IN A FULL-SPEC S.T.L.,
WHICH CAN ONLY BE FOUND HERE.
THE TREATMENT HE’S GETTING
SURPASSES WHAT
ANY HOSPITAL CAN OFFER.
HE EVEN HAS
HIS OWN FULL-TIME NURSE.
Asuna: OKAY, THEN.
I’LL TAKE YOUR WORD FOR IT.
Rinko: ALL RIGHT, KIKUOKA.
SINCE YOU’RE
IN THE MOOD TO TALK,
MIGHT AS WELL TELL US
EVERYTHING FROM THE TOP.
FIRST, WHY IS
AN S.D.F. OFFICIAL LIKE YOU
USING THE MINISTRY AS A FRONT?
NEXT, WHAT’S THE POINT OF THIS?
AND LAST,
WHY KIRIGAYA, SPECIFICALLY?
Kikuoka: IF YOU WANT ANSWERS,
YOU’LL HAVE TO SIGN ON.
Rinko: HOW ’BOUT
YOU START TALKING?
Kikuoka: ALL RIGHT, THEN.
I ASSUME YOU’RE BOTH FAMILIAR
WITH THE CONCEPT OF THE S.T.L.?
Asuna: IT READS SOULS,
OR FLUCTLIGHTS,
AS YOU CALL THEM,
AND ALLOWS THE USER TO DIVE
INTO A VIRTUAL WORLD
THAT’S INCREDIBLY LIFELIKE.
Kikuoka: THAT’S CORRECT.
AND DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THE OBJECTIVE
OF THIS PROJECT IS?
Asuna: NO, I DON’T.
Kikuoka: TO CREATE A BOTTOM-UP,
MULTIPURPOSE
ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE.
♪
♪ SHINY SWORD, MY DIAMOND ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ IT’S TIME ♪
♪
Asuna: A BOTTOM-UP,
MULTIPURPOSE A.I.?
Kikuoka: THAT’S RIGHT.
THERE ARE TWO APPROACHES
TO DEVELOPING AN A.I.
THE FIRST IS CALLED TOP-DOWN
ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE,
WHERE THE A.I. IS PROGRAMMED
WITH EXPERIENCE AND KNOWLEDGE
SO THAT IT LEARNS ENOUGH
TO APPROACH SOMETHING
CLOSE TO TRUE INTELLIGENCE.
Higa: THAT’S PRETTY MUCH
THE GIST OF IT.
EVERYTHING
THAT’S AN A.I. RIGHT NOW
IS USING THAT TOP-DOWN APPROACH.
HECK, DR. SHIGEMURA WAS
WORKIN’ WITH US HERE FOR A BIT,
AND EVEN HIS RESEARCH
FOCUSED ON THAT.
Kikuoka:
A TOP-DOWN A.I., HOWEVER,
CAN’T REACT APPROPRIATELY
TO THINGS
IT HASN’T LEARNED ABOUT.
AT THIS POINT IN TIME,
NONE HAVE EVOLVED ENOUGH
TO HAVE TRUE INTELLIGENCE.
THE SECOND APPROACH
TO A.I. DEVELOPMENT
IS CALLED BOTTOM-UP.
THE HUMAN BRAIN IS AN ORGAN
COMPRISED
OF ONE HUNDRED BILLION CELLS
CONNECTED IN INTRICATE WAYS.
THE IDEA OF BOTTOM-UP
IS RECREATING THE BRAIN
ELECTRONICALLY
AND GENERATING
TRUE INTELLIGENCE IN IT.
Asuna: BUT THAT
WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE TO DO.
Kikuoka: YOU’RE RIGHT,
AND, UNTIL NOW, IT WAS.
BUT WITH THE SOUL TRANSLATOR,
WE CAN SCAN A HUMAN SOUL,
OR SPECIFICALLY
THE QUANTUM FIELD IN BRAIN CELLS
WE CALL THE FLUCTLIGHT.
Higa: IF YOU’RE WONDERING
WHERE WE’RE GONNA PUT
ALL THE DATA OF A HUMAN BRAIN,
STOP WONDERING.
WE MADE THE LIGHT
QUANTUM GATE CRYSTAL,
OR LIGHTCUBE, TO STORE
ALL THAT GOOD STUFF ON.
Rinko: THEORETICALLY,
YOU COULD SAVE
A ONE-TO-ONE COPY
OF A FLUCTLIGHT.
Kikuoka: THAT’S CORRECT,
ALTHOUGH IT’S NOT A THEORY.
WE’VE ALREADY COPIED
A HUMAN SOUL.
( both gasp )
Rinko: BUT THEN,
WHY’D YOU BOTHER
ASKING ME TO COME HELP YOU?
Kikuoka: BECAUSE, LIKE IDIOTS,
WE MISSED SOMETHING.
THE HUMAN SOUL IS COMPLEX.
SURE, WE CAN COPY IT,
BUT THERE’S A WIDE GAP
BETWEEN IT AND A TRUE A.I.
- HIGA.
- Higa: EH?
Kikuoka: GO ON.
SHOW OUR GUESTS A DEMONSTRATION.
Higa: DAMN. YOU’RE SADISTIC.
( sighs )
Male: IS THE SAMPLING DONE YET?
Higa: YUP. NO PROBLEMS.
LOOKING GOOD.
Male: SWEET! SO WHY’S IT DARK,
AND HOW COME I CAN’T MOVE?
OH, I KNOW WHY.
LET ME OUT.
THE S.T.L.’s GLITCHIN’.
Higa: SORRY, BUDDY.
I CAN’T LOG YOU OUT.
Male: DUDE, WHAT THE HELL?
LET ME OUT OF HERE!
WHO ARE YOU?!
I DON’T RECOGNIZE YOUR VOICE!
Higa: TAKERU HIGA.
YOU KNOW THAT.
Male: WHAT?! NO WAY! I’M HIGA!
LET ME OUT, AND YOU’LL SEE!
Higa: RELAX.
YOU’RE TAKERU HIGA, THE COPY.
I KNOW YOU KNOW
WHAT’S GOING ON,
SO JUST ACCEPT
THE SITUATION AN--
Higa copy: SCREW YOU! I’M ME!
IF I’M A COPY,
THEN I’D KNOW IT, GOD DAMN IT!
COME ON! PLEASE!
LET ME OUT,
YOU SON OF A BITCH, RIGHT NOW!
Kikuoka: WE TALKED ABOUT THIS.
YOU NEED TO CALM DOWN.
IF YOU CAN’T THINK RATIONALLY,
YOUR FLUCTLIGHT WON’T BE ABLE
TO TAKE THE STRAIN.
Higa copy: I AM RATIONAL!
OKAY, THEN! LET’S SEE
WHO’S FASTER AT PI,
ME OR THAT FAKER!
3.141592653589793...
( accelerated speech, static )
( Higa sighs )
FULL COLLAPSE,
ONE MINUTE, EIGHT SECONDS.
( Asuna gags )
Rinko: ALL RIGHT,
THAT WAS BEYOND TWISTED!
Kikuoka: IT IS DISTURBING.
STILL, IT’S THE BEST WAY
TO EXPLAIN
WHAT WE’VE BEEN ABLE
TO ACCOMPLISH UP TO NOW.
I’M SORRY YOU HAD TO SEE IT.
WE COPIED OVER A DOZEN
FLUCTLIGHTS, INCLUDING MINE,
AND SUBMITTED THEM
TO THE SAME TEST.
THE RESULTS
WERE ALWAYS THE SAME.
THEIR LOGIC SYSTEMS WENT
HAYWIRE, AND THEY COLLAPSED.
SINCE MATURE FLUCTLIGHTS
DON’T WORK,
WHAT WOULD YOU TRY NEXT?
Rinko: MAYBE WIPE
THEIR MEMORIES.
OR RAISE A SOUL FROM SCRATCH.
Asuna: YOU DIDN’T.
Kikuoka: YES, WE DID.
WE PUT NEWBORNS INTO THE S.T.L.
AND COPIED THEIR SOULS.
( both gasp )
Rinko: THESE COPIES
ARE ESSENTIALLY HUMAN,
SO HOW WOULD YOU RAISE THEM?
NOT IN A VOID.
YOU’D NEED AN EXACT COPY
OF THE REAL WORLD.
Kikuoka: THAT’S IMPOSSIBLE.
WE CAN’T DO THAT YET,
SO WE WENT LOOKING
FOR AN ALTERNATIVE,
AND WE FOUND IT ONLINE.
Asuna: V.R.M.M.O. WORLDS.
Higa: DANG, YOU’RE SHARP.
USING THE SEED,
WE MADE OUR OWN WORLD,
WITH VILLAGES AND TERRAIN,
AND CONVERTED IT
TO MNEMONIC VISUALS
FOR THE S.T.L.
Kikuoka: WE PLACED
FOUR OF OUR STAFF
IN THE FIRST VILLAGE WE CREATED.
THEY ACTED AS PARENTS
TO 16 A.I. INFANTS,
OR SOUL ARCHETYPES,
AND RAISED THEM
’TIL THEY WERE 18.
WE MONITORED THE YOUNGSTERS
AS THEY GREW UP.
OH, BY THE WAY,
OFFICIALLY, WE CALL THEM
ARTIFICIAL FLUCTLIGHTS.
ANYWAY, WE WERE
MORE THAN SATISFIED
WITH HOW THEY TURNED OUT.
THEY WERE SHARP,
OBEDIENT, AND UPSTANDING.
WHEN THEY EVENTUALLY PAIRED UP,
WE MADE THEM PARENTS
AND GAVE THEM
NEW SOUL ARCHETYPES TO RAISE.
OUR STAFF WAS OUT BY THEN,
SO WE ACCELERATED TIME
BY 5,000,
AND SOON WE HAD
MULTIPLE GENERATIONS.
AFTER THREE WEEKS
HAD PASSED IN OUR WORLD,
300 HAD PASSED IN THEIRS.
NOW THEY HAVE
A FULLY FUNCTIONING SOCIETY
WITH A POPULATION OF 80,000.
Rinko: YOU SIMULATED
AN ENTIRE CIVILIZATION.
Kikuoka: EXACTLY.
SO FAR, 480 YEARS
HAVE PASSED THERE.
THE CAPITAL, CENTORIA,
HAS 20,000 CITIZENS
LIVING IN IT.
Higa: AT THIS POINT,
ALL THE A.I. FLUCTLIGHTS
HAVE MATURED
INTO THE BOTTOM-UP A.I.s
WE WERE SHOOTING FOR.
WE WERE ALL READY
TO HIT THE NEXT PHASE
AND WERE STOKED ABOUT IT,
BUT THEN...
Kikuoka: WE NOTICED
A MAJOR ISSUE
WHICH STOOD IN OUR WAY.
Rinko: WHAT ISSUE?
Kikuoka:
THE GOVERNING BODY THERE,
CALLED THE AXIOM CHURCH,
CREATED A SET OF LAWS
CALLED THE TABOO INDEX.
Asuna: THE WHAT INDEX?
Kikuoka: THE TABOO INDEX.
IT CONTAINS LAWS
LIKE ONE FORBIDDING MURDER,
JUST LIKE WE HAVE.
AND, IF YOU’VE BEEN
WATCHING THE NEWS RECENTLY,
YOU CAN SEE HOW DIFFICULT
THAT ONE IS FOR HUMANS TO OBEY,
BUT THE FLUCTLIGHTS OBEY
ALL THEIR LAWS TO THE LETTER.
THEY’RE OBSESSIVE ABOUT IT.
THIS TOWN IS BEAUTIFUL,
BUT TOO PERFECT.
THERE’S NO LITTER
ON THE STREETS
AND NO CRIME TO SPEAK OF.
NEEDLESS TO SAY,
THERE’S NOT BEEN
A SINGLE MURDER
COMMITTED HERE, EITHER.
Rinko: AND THAT WOULD BE
A GOOD THING, WOULDN’T IT?
Asuna: IT WOULDN’T,
NOT FOR HIM, ANYWAY.
HE WANTS A.I.s THAT CAN KILL.
( Rinko gasps )
Asuna: KIRITO AND I WERE WRONG.
WE THOUGHT WE KNEW
WHY YOU WERE INTERESTED
IN V.R.M.M.O.s, FOR TRAINING.
WE FIGURED
YOU’D USE THE TECHNOLOGY
TO TRAIN SOLDIERS AND POLICE.
BUT FOR AN OFFICER OF THE S.D.F.
TO ATTEMPT
SOMETHING ON THIS SCALE,
THERE HAS TO BE MORE AT STAKE,
AND THERE IS.
THIS PROJECT IS ABOUT
CREATING A.I. FOR WARFARE,
ISN’T IT?
Rinko: IS THAT TRUE, KIKUOKA?
Kikuoka: FIVE YEARS AGO,
WHEN THE NERVEGEAR WAS
FIRST ANNOUNCED, I HAD AN IDEA.
ALTHOUGH IT WAS MEANT
FOR GAMING, THIS NEW TECHNOLOGY
HAD THE POTENTIAL
TO CHANGE HOW WARS WERE FOUGHT.
WHEN THE "S.A.O."
INCIDENT HAPPENED,
I ASKED TO BE TRANSFERRED
TO THE MINISTRY,
THEN JOINED
THE TASK FORCE THERE.
THAT WAS ALL SO I COULD GET
THIS PROJECT OFF THE GROUND,
AND FIVE YEARS LATER,
HERE WE ARE.
Rinko: THAT’S HIS REASON,
BUT WHY DID YOU DECIDE
TO TAKE PART IN THIS?
Higa: OH. UM,
THAT’S A WHOLE ’NOTHER STORY.
FOR ME, IT’S PERSONAL.
WHEN I WAS IN COLLEGE,
I HAD A BUD IN KOREA
WHO WAS IN THE ARMY THERE.
THEN HE GOT KILLED
ON ONE OF HIS TOURS.
SO I THOUGHT THIS STUPID WORLD
AIN’T GONNA STOP
HAVIN’ WARS ANYTIME SOON.
BUT IF WE COULD FIGURE OUT
HOW TO HAVE ’EM
WITHOUT KILLING PEOPLE, THEN...
( chuckles )
SOUNDS NAÏVE, RIGHT?
Asuna: YOU DIDN’T
TELL KIRITO ANY OF THIS
BEFORE YOU HIRED HIM, DID YOU?
Kikuoka: WOULD IT
MATTER IF I DID?
Asuna: YES, IT WOULD HAVE.
IF YOU HAD TOLD HIM, HE NEVER
WOULD HAVE AGREED TO HELP.
THERE’S ONE IMPORTANT ISSUE
YOUR PLAN DOESN’T EVEN ADDRESS.
Kikuoka: WHICH IS?
Asuna: THE RIGHTS OF THE A.I.s.
THESE THINGS YOU CALL
ARTIFICIAL FLUCTLIGHTS,
THEY’RE STILL MENTALLY
AND EMOTIONALLY HUMAN.
Kikuoka: TRUE, BUT IT’S NOT
LIKE THEY HAVE PHYSICAL BODIES.
Asuna: BUT OTHERWISE,
THEY’RE NO DIFFERENT FROM US,
AND YOU’RE FORCING THEM
TO BE YOUR TOOLS OF WAR.
KIRITO WOULD NEVER
AGREE TO THAT, EVER.
Kikuoka: LOOK, I UNDERSTAND
THE POINT YOU’RE
TRYING TO MAKE HERE.
BUT, TO ME,
THE LIFE OF ONE S.D.F. SOLDIER
IS WORTH FAR MORE
THAN 100,000 A.I.s.
Rinko: ANYWAY, WHY DID YOU
NEED KIRIGAYA FOR THIS?
I CAN’T UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU’D USE A CIVILIAN
ON A PROJECT
THAT’S SO CONFIDENTIAL.
Kikuoka: I’M SORRY.
I GOT SO CARRIED AWAY
TALKING ABOUT THE PROJECT,
I ALMOST FORGOT.
WE NEEDED TO KNOW
WHY THE A.I. FLUCTLIGHTS
COULDN’T DISOBEY
THE TABOO INDEX,
SO I CAME UP
WITH AN EXPERIMENT.
IF WE BLOCKED
A HUMAN’S MEMORIES,
REVERTED HIM TO CHILDHOOD,
AND HAD HIM GROW UP
IN OUR V.R. WORLD,
WOULD HE BE ABLE
TO DISOBEY THE TABOO INDEX?
TO CARRY THIS OUT,
WE NEEDED SOMEONE
WITH EXPERIENCE
NAVIGATING
IN A V.R. ENVIRONMENT,
NOT JUST A WEEK OR
A MONTH’S WORTH OF EXPERIENCE.
I’M TALKING YEARS.
( Asuna gasps )
Kikuoka:
THAT’S WHY I NEEDED HIM.
Leafa: I CAN’T BELIEVE KAZUTO
WOULD SIGN UP
FOR SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
( Silica sighs )
CAN WE EVEN TRUST
ANYTHING KIKUOKA SAYS ANYMORE?
Lisbeth: I BET HE ONLY TOLD YOU
A FRACTION
OF WHAT HE’S REALLY UP TO.
Sinon: I GUESS ALL WE CAN DO NOW
IS HOPE THE TREATMENT KIRITO
GETS IN THE S.T.L. WILL WORK.
( Silica sighs )
Lisbeth: WHAT HAPPENED
WITH THAT TABOO INDEX THING,
YOU KNOW, THE EXPERIMENT?
DID HE TELL YOU IF IT WORKED?
Asuna: MM-HMM.
KIRITO GOT TO BE CLOSE FRIENDS
WITH TWO OTHERS,
A BOY AND A GIRL.
KIKUOKA SAID THE GIRL ENDED UP
BREAKING ONE OF THE LAWS.
Sinon: REALLY?
DID SHE DO IT BECAUSE OF KIRITO?
Asuna: UH-HUH.
APPARENTLY, SHE VIOLATED A TABOO
BY TRYING TO ACCESS
A RESTRICTED ADDRESS.
Higa: ACCORDING TO THE LOG,
THE GIRL SAW
ANOTHER A.I. FLUCTLIGHT
DIE IN THE RESTRICTED AREA,
AND, FROM WHAT WE CAN TELL,
SHE WAS TRYING TO SAVE HIM.
Kikuoka: SHE HAD MORE CONCERN
FOR ANOTHER PERSON’S LIFE
THAN SHE HAD
FOR DISOBEYING THE TABOO INDEX.
SHE CHOSE TO DO IT, AND THAT’S
WHAT WE’RE LOOKING FOR.
( girls grumble )
Silica: THAT’S KIND OF
A NEAT STORY.
Lisbeth: YEAH, IF ONLY IT WASN’T
ABOUT TRAINING A.I.s
TO KILL PEOPLE.
Asuna: YOU’RE RIGHT.
BUT LOOK AT WHAT SHE DID.
SHE WENT AGAINST THE SYSTEM
JUST TO HELP SOMEONE ELSE.
Leafa: DOES THIS
A.I. GIRL HAVE A NAME?
Asuna: YES.
ALICE?
Kikuoka: THAT’S RIGHT.
I WAS STUNNED
WHEN I FOUND OUT.
HER HAVING THAT NAME
IS QUITE THE COINCIDENCE.
THE NAME ALICE, YOU SEE,
ALSO HAPPENS TO BE
THE NAME OF THE CONCEPT
THAT WAS THE FOUNDATION
FOR RATH AND THIS PROJECT.
Asuna: CONCEPT?
Kikuoka: AN A.I. THAT IS
HIGHLY ADAPTIVE AND AUTONOMOUS,
MORE SPECIFICALLY,
AN ARTIFICIAL
LABILE INTELLIGENCE
CYBERNATED EXISTENCE,
OR THE ACRONYM "ALICE."
OUR GOAL ULTIMATELY
WAS TO TURN AN A.I. FLUCTLIGHT
INTO AN ALICE.
THEREFORE, WE CALLED IT
PROJECT ALICIZATION.
Leafa: THAT SOUNDS
SO COMPLICATED.
Asuna: YEAH. I DON’T UNDERSTAND
A LOT OF WHAT HE SAID, EITHER.
BUT HE SAID IF THEY
HAD SAVED ALICE’S FLUCTLIGHT,
THEIR RESEARCH WOULD BE
MUCH FURTHER ALONG BY NOW.
Lisbeth: MM. DID SHE DIE?
Asuna: NO, SHE’S STILL ALIVE,
BUT REMEMBER I SAID
TIME THERE’S FASTER THAN HERE?
Lisbeth: MM-HMM.
Asuna: WELL,
BY THE TIME THEY NOTICED,
TWO DAYS HAD GONE BY THERE.
SHE WAS TAKEN TO THE CAPITAL,
AND THE AXIOM CHURCH
HAD HER FLUCTLIGHT ALTERED.
Sinon: THEY CHANGED HER SOUL?
HOW COULD THEY
GIVE A.I. FLUCTLIGHTS
THAT KIND OF AUTHORITY
OVER EACH OTHER?
Asuna: THEY DON’T
REALLY KNOW HOW IT HAPPENED,
BUT THEY THINK IT MIGHT BE
A SYSTEM EXPLOIT.
A FEW OF THE A.I. FLUCTLIGHTS
CAN USE
WHAT THEY CALL "SACRED ARTS."
THEY’RE BASICALLY
SYSTEM ACCESS AUTHORITIES
THAT LOOK LIKE MAGIC SPELLS.
( gasps ) SORRY.
I HAVE TO LOG OUT NOW.
Leafa: WHY? WHAT’S THE RUSH?
Asuna: THEY SAID THEY’D LET ME
LOOK IN ON KIRITO FOR A BIT.
I DON’T WANT
TO BE LATE FOR THAT.
Lisbeth: YOU GET
TO WATCH HIM SLEEP.
TELL US IF HE DROOLS.
( Asuna laughs )
I DON’T THINK I’LL SEE HIS FACE.
THE MACHINE HE’S IN
COVERS IT UP.
♪
Rinko: EH?
NUMBER FOUR...
AND THAT’S FIVE.
Aki: THEY’RE STILL
BUILDING UNIT SIX.
IT’S IN ROPPONGI
WITH UNIT ONE, THE PROTOTYPE.
TWO AND THREE ARE HERE.
WELL, ACTUALLY THEY’RE
IN THE LOWER SHAFT.
- Asuna: MS. AKI.
- ( Aki chuckles )
Asuna: WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
Aki: I’M TAKING CARE
OF KIRIGAYA.
Asuna: BUT YOU WERE HIS NURSE
AT THAT HOSPITAL IN CHIYODA.
( gasps ) WAIT.
ARE YOU A NURSE,
OR ARE YOU JUST FAKING?!
Aki: I’M A NURSE.
I’M REGISTERED AND EVERYTHING
AND HAVE
THE PAPERS TO PROVE IT.
ALTHOUGH, FULL DISCLOSURE,
THE NURSING SCHOOL
I GRADUATED FROM
IS AFFILIATED WITH
THE TOKYO SELF-DEFENSE FORCE.
( Asuna gasps )
Aki: SERGEANT FIRST CLASS
NATSUKI AKI.
AS LONG AS I’M ON DUTY HERE,
I SWEAR I WILL PROTECT KIRIGAYA.
WE GOOD?
( Asuna sighs )
YEAH. WE’RE GOOD.
Aki: DON’T YOU WORRY
ABOUT A THING.
♪
Asuna: IN YOUR OPINION,
WILL HE BE OKAY?
Aki: OF COURSE HE WILL.
HIS FLUCTLIGHT’S STABLE SO FAR,
AND HIS NEURAL NETWORK’S
ON THE MEND.
ALL HIS VITALS
ARE LOOKING GOOD, TOO.
HE IS A TOUGH COOKIE.
HE’S THE ONE
WHO CLEARED "S.A.O.," AFTER ALL.
( Rinko sighs )
CAN WE TALK?
Asuna: EH? HUH?
Rinko: THERE’S...
SOMETHING I HAVE
TO CONFESS TO YOU.
MM-MMM. NOT JUST TO YOU.
I OWE ONE
TO ALL THE "S.A.O." PLAYERS,
LIVING AND DEAD.
( Asuna sighs )
Rinko: I’M SURE
YOU HEARD THE STORY
ABOUT HOW,
DURING THE "S.A.O." INCIDENT,
AKIHIKO KAYABA AND I WERE HIDING
IN THE MOUNTAINS OF NAGANO?
THAT SCAR’S FROM A MICRO-BOMB
AKIHIKO IMPLANTED THERE.
( Asuna gasps )
Rinko: THE NEWS
SAID HE PUT IT THERE
TO FORCE ME TO STAY
AND HELP HIM WITH HIS PLAN
DURING THOSE TWO YEARS,
BUT THAT’S NOT THE TRUTH.
YES, THE BOMB WAS REAL,
BUT I KNEW
IT WOULD NEVER GO OFF.
HE PUT IT THERE
SO THAT, WHEN WE WERE CAUGHT,
I WOULDN’T BE CHARGED
WITH AIDING AND ABETTING.
IT WAS A BLUFF TO KEEP ME SAFE
AND THE ONLY PRESENT
HE EVER GAVE ME.
WHEN AKIHIKO GOT INTO THE TOTO
INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY,
HE WAS ALREADY
HEAD OF DEVELOPMENT AT ARGUS,
BUT I DIDN’T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
ALL I SAW WAS A SCRAWNY LONER
WHO ONLY CARED
ABOUT HIS RESEARCH.
YOU WANT SOME INSPIRATION?
THEN GET OUT ONCE IN A WHILE!
( Kayaba stammers )
I NEED TO FIND A WAY
TO EMULATE THE FEELING
OF SUNLIGHT ON THE SKIN.
Rinko: WHAT?
WE WERE TOTAL OPPOSITES,
BUT WE STARTED DATING.
( no audible dialogue )
ONE THING
I COULD NEVER FIGURE OUT
WAS WHY HE WANTED
TO STAY WITH ME.
THE OTHER WAS HIM.
ALL THAT TIME TOGETHER...
AND I DIDN’T KNOW HIM AT ALL.
I KNEW AKIHIKO WAS AT HIS CABIN,
BUT I DIDN’T GO THERE
BECAUSE I WANTED TO HELP HIM.
I...
I WENT, BECAUSE I
WANTED TO KILL HIM.
( Asuna gasps )
Rinko: AND THEN,
I DON’T KNOW WHY, BUT I-I...
I COULDN’T DO IT.
HE KNEW WHAT I WAS THINKING
AND THAT I HAD A KNIFE,
BUT HE JUST SMILED AND SAID,
"WHAT AM I GONNA DO WITH YOU?"
LIKE HE ALWAYS DID,
AND THEN HE WENT
BACK TO AINCRAD.
( crying )
OH, GOD. I’M SO SORRY.
Asuna: KIRITO AND I
NEVER BLAMED YOU
OR HATED YOU FOR ANYTHING.
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I CAN’T REALLY SAY
I HATE THE COMMANDER, EITHER.
I-I MEAN AKIHIKO KAYABA.
♪
I’M NOT SAYING HE SHOULD
BE FORGIVEN FOR WHAT HE DID.
HE SHOULDN’T.
A LOT OF LIVES WERE LOST.
BUT STILL--
AND THIS MAY SOUND
A LITTLE SELFISH--
I WOULDN’T TRADE ANYTHING
FOR THE TIME I GOT TO SPEND
LIVING THERE WITH KIRITO.
HONESTLY, TO ME, THOSE WERE
THE BEST DAYS OF MY LIFE.
( Rinko gasps )
Asuna: YES, THE COMMANDER
COMMITTED A CRIME,
AND SO DID KIRITO AND I,
AND YOU DID, TOO.
WE ALL DID SOMETHING WRONG,
AND, IN THE END,
EVEN IF WE’RE PUNISHED,
THERE’S NO WAY TO MAKE IT RIGHT.
I DON’T THINK THE DAY WILL
EVER COME WHEN WE’RE FORGIVEN.
ALL WE CAN DO IS OWN UP TO IT.
THERE’S NO CHOICE BUT
TO FACE OUR SINS AND KEEP GOING.
( footsteps )
Kayaba: COMING ALL
THE WAY OUT HERE?
( scoffs )
WHAT AM I GONNA DO WITH YOU?
( Rinko gasps )
IT’S SO EARLY.
COME BACK TO BED.
( gasps )
( panting )
( sighs )
WAS THAT...
A DREAM?
♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ THE IRIS TO YOU ♪